window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "C_Programming - Function — Slot 4 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Function — Slot 4",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>What is the time complexity for the following C module? Assume that \\(n \\gt 0\\).<br><pre><code>\nint module(int n)\n{\n    if (n == 1)\n        return 1;\n    else\n        return (n + module(n-1));\n}</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>O(n)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(O(\\log n)\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(O\\left(n^{2}\\right)\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>O(n!)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>O(n)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55082/isro2014-67\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following is true with respect to Reference? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A reference can never be NULL</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>A reference needs an explicit dereferencing mechanism</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>A reference can be reassigned after it is established</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A reference and pointer are synonymous</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>A reference can never be NULL</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/17420/isro2014-13\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Consider the C function given below<pre><code> int f(int j)\n{\nstatic int i = 50;\nint k;\nif (i == j)\n{\nprintf(\"something\");\nk = f(i);\nreturn 0;\n}\nelse return 0;\n} </code></pre>\nWhich one of the following is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>The function returns 0 for all values of j.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The function prints the string something for all values of j.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The function returns 0 when j = 50.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The function will exhaust the runtime stack or run into an infinite loop when j = 50</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>The function will exhaust the runtime stack or run into an infinite loop when j = 50</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2008/gate2014-2-42#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following function<pre><code> double f (double x) {\nif ( abs (x*x - 3) &lt; 0. 01) return x;\nelse return f (x / 2 + 1.5/x);\n} </code></pre>\nGive a value q (to 2 decimals) such that f(q) will return q:______ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "1.72",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2000/gate2014-2-40#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Consider the function func shown below:<pre><code> int func(int num) {\nint count = 0;\nwhile (num) {\n    count++;\n    num &gt;&gt; = 1;\n}\nreturn (count);\n} </code></pre>\nThe value returned by func(435)is __________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "9",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1964/gate2014-2-10#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following psuedocode:<br><pre><code>x: integer := 1  \ny: integer := 2   \nprocedure add  \n    x:= x + y    \nprocedure second (P: Procedure)  \n    x: integer := 2      \n    p()   \nprocedure first  \n    y: integer := 3\n    second (add) \nfirst () \nwrite_integer(x) </code></pre> What does it print if the language uses dynamic scoping with deep binding? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>4</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>5</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>4</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43764/isro-2013-7\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>What is the return value of f(p,p), if the value of p is initialized to 5 before the call? Note that\nthe first parameter is passed by reference, whereas the second parameter is passed by value.<pre><code> int f (int &amp;x, int c) {\n  c = c - 1;\n  if (c==0) return 1;\n   x = x + 1;\nreturn f(x,c) * x;\n} </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>3024</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>6561</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>55440</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>161051</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>6561</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/60/gate2013-42#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C code segment.<pre><code>\nint a, b, c = 0;\nvoid prtFun(void);\nmain( )\n{ static int a = 1; /* Line 1 */\n   prtFun( );\n   a += 1;\n   prtFun( );\n   printf(\" \\n %d %d \", a, b);\n}\nvoid prtFun(void)\n{ static int a = 2; /* Line 2 */\n   int b = 1;\n   a += ++b;\n   printf(\" \\n %d %d \", a, b);\n}</code></pre>What output will be generated by the given code segment if: <br><br>\nLine 1 is replaced by auto int a = 1; <br>\nLine 2 is replaced by register int a = 2; <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>3 1 <br>\n4 1 <br>\n4 2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>4 2 <br>\n6 1<br>\n6 1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>4 2<br>\n6 2<br>\n2 0</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>4 2<br>\n4 2<br>\n2 0</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>4 2<br>\n4 2<br>\n2 0</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43314/gate2012-49#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following C code segment.<pre><code>\nint a, b, c = 0;\nvoid prtFun(void);\nmain( )\n{ static int a = 1; /* Line 1 */\n   prtFun( );\n   a += 1;\n   prtFun( );\n   printf(\" \\n %d %d \", a, b);\n}\nvoid prtFun(void)\n{ static int a = 2; /* Line 2 */\n   int b = 1;\n   a += ++b;\n   printf(\" \\n %d %d \", a, b);\n}</code></pre>What output will be generated by the given code segment? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>3 1<br>\n4 1 <br>\n4 2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>4 2<br>\n6 1 <br>\n6 1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>4 2 <br>\n6 2 <br>\n2 0</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>3 1 <br>\n5 2 <br>\n5 2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>4 2 <br>\n6 2 <br>\n2 0</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2176/gate2012-48#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following recursive C function that takes two arguments<pre><code> unsigned int foo(unsigned int n, unsigned int r) {\n  if (n  &gt; 0) return (n%r +  foo (n/r, r ));\n  else return 0;\n}</code></pre>What is the return value of the function foo when it is called as foo (513, 2)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>9</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>8</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>5</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>2</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43324/gate2011-49#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following recursive C function that takes two arguments<pre><code> unsigned int foo(unsigned int n, unsigned int r) {\n  if (n  &gt; 0) return (n%r +  foo (n/r, r ));\n  else return 0;\n}</code></pre>   <br>What is the return value of the function foo when it is called as foo (345, 10) ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>345</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>12</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>5</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>3</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>12</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2154/gate2011-48#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>What is the value printed by the following C program?<pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint f(int * a, int n)\n{\n    if(n&lt;=0)return 0;\n    else if(*a% 2 ==0) return *a+f(a+1,n-1);\n    else return *a-f(a+1,n-1);\n}\nint main ( )\n{\n    int a[ ] {12, 7, 13, 4, 11, 6};\n    printf (\"%d\", f(a,6));\n    return 0;\n} </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>-9</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>5</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>15</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>19</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>15</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2336/gate2010-35#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>What does the following program print?<pre><code> #include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nvoid f (int *p, int * q) {\n       p=q;\n       *p=2;\n}\nint i= 0, j= 1;\nint main ( ){\n     f(&amp;i, &amp; j);\n     printf( \"%d%d \\ n\", i,j);\n     return 0;\n} </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2 2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>2 1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>0 1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>0 2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>0 2</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2184/gate2010-11#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following code written in a pass-by-reference language like FORTRAN and these statements about the code. <br><pre><code> subroutine swap(ix,iy) \n     it = ix \nL1 : ix = iy \nL2 : iy = it \n    end \n    ia = 3 \n    ib = 8 \n    call swap (ia, ib+5)\n    print *, ia, ib \n    end </code></pre><br>S1: The compiler will  generate code to allocate a temporary nameless cell, initialize it to 13, and pass the address of the cell to swap <br>\nS2: On execution the code will generate a runtime error on line L1 <br>\nS3: On execution the code will generate a runtime error on line L2 <br>\nS4: The program will print 13 and 8 <br>\nS5: The program will print 13 and -2 <br>\nExactly the following set of statement(s) is correct: <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>S1 and S2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>S1 and S4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>S3</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>S1 and S5</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>S1 and S4</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1834/gate2006-56-isro2009-58\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Consider the program below:<pre><code> # include &lt; stdio.h &gt;\nint fun(int n, int * f_p) {\n   int t, f;\n   if (n &lt;=1) {\n         *f_p =1;\n          return 1;\n   }\n   t = fun (n-1, f_p);\n   f = t+*f_p;\n   *f_p = t;\n   return f;\n}\nint main() {\n    int x = 15;\n    printf (\"%d\\ n\", fun(5,&amp; x));\n    return 0;\n} </code></pre>\nThe value printed is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>6</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>8</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>14</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>15</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>8</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1310/gate2009-18#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
